Guide to the Richard E. Snow Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Richard E. Snow papers
1965-1997
SC0590
Snow, Richard E.
32.5 Linear feet
This collection consists of two parts: Snow's reference files compiled while serving as liaison scientist for psychology in Europe and the Middle East for the U.S. Office of Naval Research in London, 1983-85, and his professional papers, 1965-1997. The first part contains his correspondence with researchers and copies of their published and unpublished work, arranged by location. His professional papers include correspondence, memoranda, minutes, reports, notes, publications, papers, and other items pertaining to the Stanford School of Education, the Committee on Educational Policy, classes, conferences he attended, and other matters.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Transfer from the School of Education, Stanford University, 2000-2003.
Information about Access
Letters of recommendation are restricted. The collection is otherwise open for research. Materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Richard E. Snow, professor of education at Stanford from 1967 until his death in 1997, first came to Stanford University in 1966 as a research associate for the Stanford Center for Research and Development in Teaching. He earned his master's and doctoral degrees in psychology from Purdue University and taught there before coming to Stanford. From 1983 to 1985, Snow served as liaison scientist for psychology in Europe and the Middle East for the U.S. Office of Naval Research in London. A specialist on learning styles, Snow was the author of three books, more than 50 book chapters, and 40 journal articles. He held honorary doctoral degrees from the University of Gothenburg in Sweden and the University of Leuven, Belgium. He was elected to the National Academy of Education in 1993.
Description of the Collection
This collection consists of two parts: Snow's reference files compiled while serving as liaison scientist for psychology in Europe and the Middle East for the U.S. Office of Naval Research in London, 1983-85, and his professional papers, 1965-1997. The first part contains his correspondence with researchers and copies of their published and unpublished work, arranged by location. His professional papers include correspondence, memoranda, minutes, reports, notes, publications, papers, and other items pertaining to the Stanford School of Education, the Committee on Educational Policy, classes, conferences he attended, and other matters.
Access Terms
Snow, Richard E.; Stanford University. School of Education..; United States. Office of Naval Research. Branch Office, London.; Learning, Psychology of.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2000-150
  - Reference files as liaison scientist for psychology in Europe and the Middle East for the U. S. Office of Naval Research in London, 1983-1985; Subseries 1
    - General Files
      - European Scientific Notes (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Technology Review (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Nick Bond’s ENS articles (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Contacts
      - Master contact file (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Dr. Snow files (add.) (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Euro – Cognitive Science Directory (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Intelligent Tutoring Systems in Europe (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous International Journals (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Germany – General (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Nurnburg, Hamburg, Kiel, Berlin (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - France – Lyon Grenoble (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Further Italy Contacts (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Israel (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Netherlands (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Dutch Trip II (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Norway (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Sweden – Goteborg (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Switzerland (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Other British Contacts (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - EARLI
      - De Corte Conference Program (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - EARLI Conference – June 10--13, 1985 – Leuven, Belgium (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Second EARLI Conference (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Sign--up sheets for Snow’s European Lit File (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Australia
      - J.B. Biggs (Newcastle) (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Ian Smith (Sydney) (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Austria
      - Kongress der Deutschen Gesellschaft fur Psychologie (Vienna) (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Neumaier, Weingartner (Salzburg) (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Guttmann and Bavor (Vienna) (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Rollett (Vienna) (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Thonhauser, Krumm, Neubauer, Gattringer (Salzburg) (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Wimmer (Salzburg) (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Belgium
      - Bohrer and De Seote (Brussels) (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Claeys (Leuven) (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - De Boeck (Leuven) (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Delhaye (Leuven) (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Janssen (Leuven) (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Lambrochts (Oostende) (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Dr. Lens (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - Lowyck (Leuven) (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - Mervielde (Gent) (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Nuttin (Leuven) (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Tistaert (Leuven) (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - UCODI (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Van Damme (Leuven) (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Vandierendonck (Ghent) (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Van Longenhove (Brussels) (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Van Overwalle (Free University Brussels) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - D’Ydewalle (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Brazil
      - Pacca Villani, Hosoume (San Paulo – physics) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Denmark
      - Busch--Jensen (Copenhagen) (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Lybeck (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Miscellaneous Denmark (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Finland
      - Miscellaneous Finland (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Leino (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Ronkonen (Helsinki) (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - France
      - Paris, Bordeaux,Aix en Provence (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Laboratoire de Psychologie Differentielle Service de Recherches de L’I.N.O.P. (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Laboratoire de Psychologie Experimentale (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Artemenko (Bordeaux) (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Barratt Council of Europe (Strasbourg) (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Bacher (Paris) (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Bajard (Bordeaux) (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Bressen--Vergnaud (Paris) (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Crocq, Fourcade, Lyon (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Gilly (Aix en Provence) (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Guiard (Marseille) – Left-handedness (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Lautrey (Paris) (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Leve--Schoen, O’Regan (Paris) (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Longeot, Ohlmann, and Others (Grenoble) (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Marquer (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Piolat (Aix en Provence) (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Wittner (Bordeaux) (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Germany
      - Achtenhagen (Gottingen) (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Amelang (Heidelburg) (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Chapman (Max Planck Institute – Berlin) (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Baltes (Berlin) (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous Documents from Max Planck Institute (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Bart--U. of Minn visiting Max Planck Institute in Munich (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Cavonius (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Doerner (Bamburg) (Box 3, Folder 89)
      - Duit (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Feger (Hamburg) (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Frey, Haussler, Rost (Kiel) – IPN (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Heidt (Bielefeld) (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Herrmann (Mannheim) (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Arbeiten der Forschungsgruppe – Sprache und Kognition (contains Herrmann) (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Eine Mehrklassige Kunstsprache (Herrmann and Schell) (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Partnerbezogenes Berichten: Perspektive, Fokus, und Linearisierung (Herrmann, et al.) (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Zur Maschinellen Klassifikation von Aufforderungen (Herrman and Mangold) (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Hofer (Mannheim) (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Hornke (Dusseldorf) (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Issing (Berlin) (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Jager (Berlin) (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Jungermann (T.U. Berlin) (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Echterhoff (Traffic Safety Research Institute) (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Institut fur Bildungs und Beratungsforschung (Univ. of Frankfurt) (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Psychologischer Dienst der Bundeswehr (Bonn) (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Kaminski (Tubingen) (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Klauer, K.J. (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Klauer, cont. (Aachen) (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Manol (Tubingen) (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Nenninger, Aurin (Freiburg) (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Pawlik (Hamburg) (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Sander (Aachen) (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Petzold (Dusseldorf) (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Postlethwaite – IEA (Hamburg) (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Rauch – Military Testing Association (MTA) (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Rosler (Kiel) (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Roth (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Sanders (Aachen) (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Schieber and Sellin (Hamburg) (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Schneider, Treiber -- Max Planck Assoc. in Munich (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Schwarzer (Berlin) (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Stapf (Tubingen) (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Strube -- Max Planck Assoc. in Munich (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Wenzel (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Winterhoff--Spurk (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Wittmann (Freiburg) (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Book -- Design of Work in Automated Manufacturing Systems (T. Martin) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Greece
      - Miscellaneous loose letters to: Paraskevopolous; Porpodas; Houssiades; Demetriou and Efklides; Markoulis (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Demetriou and Efklides (Thessaloniki) (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Demetriou – Visiting Scientist (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Georgas et al. (Athens) (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Porpodas (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Haritos--Fatouros (Thessaloniki) (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Markoulis (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Ireland-Hungary
      - Falus, Andor et al. (Budapest) (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Kellaghan (Goggin) (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Israel
      - Bar--Tal (Tel Aviv) (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Feuerstein (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Globerson (Tel Aviv) (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Hativa (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Kreitler (Tel Aviv) (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Mansdorf (Tel Aviv) (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Nachmias (Tel Aviv) (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Peled (Beer Sheva) (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Shoham--Salomon (Tel--Aviv) (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Strauss (Tel Aviv) (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Zakay (Tel Aviv) (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Italy
      - Barolo (Milan) (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Bisiacchi (Padua) (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - Colombetti et al. (Milan) (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - Gemelli (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Gerbino, Luccio, Kanisza, Zanuttini (Trieste) (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - Mettelli, Zanforlin, Vicario, Marzi, Masin, Cornoldi, Casio (Padua) (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Parisi (Rome) (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Poli (Milan) (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Pontecorvo (Rome) (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Tabossi (Bologna) (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Umilta (Parma) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Japan
      - Haga and Egawa (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Iwawaki (Hyogo) (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Education (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Netherlands
      - Boekaerts (Nijmegen) (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Bol, Peeck et al. (Utrecht) (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Boonman, Kanselaar, van der Linden (Utrecht) (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Dept of Gov. – Creemers and Koster (Groningen) (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Creemers and Koster (Groningen) (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Semantic Decision – T.M. Chang (not in folder) (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Crombag (Leiden) (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Crombag, cont. (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Crombag – International Symposium on Educational Testing (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Crombag, De Wijkerslooth, and van Tuyl van Serooskerken (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Crombag – Net Study Load (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Flores D’Arcais (Leiden) (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - de Groot (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - de Klerk (Tilburg) (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - de Leeuw (VU Amsterdam) (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - S. Dijkstra (Twente) (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - W. Dijkstra (VU Amsterdam) (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Elshout (Amsterdam) (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Fokkema Group (VU Amsterdam) (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Groot (Tilburg) (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - Halkes (Tilburg) (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Hettema (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Hettema, cont. (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - van Heck and Hettema (empty folder) (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - Hofstee (Groningen) (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - Hudson – Left--handedness (TNO) (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - Ippel (VU Amsterdam) (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - Pilot and Mettes (Twente) (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Institute for Perception Research (IPO) – Endhoven (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Kieviet (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Krammer (Enschede) (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Liebrand (Groningen) (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Max Planck Institute for Psycholinguistics at Nijmegen (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Michon and Jackson (Groningen) (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Pieters (Twente) (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Plomp (Twente) (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Plomp, cont. (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Poortinga (Tilburg) (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Smid (Groningen) (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - P. Span – ATI (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - P. Span, Pennings (Utrecht) (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - P. Span (Utrecht) (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - P. Span, Plomp, and Verhoeven (empty folder) (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - P. Span, van Lier, and Smuling (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Thijs (Delft) (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - Ten Berge (Groningen) (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - Thung (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - van den Akker (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - van der Kamp (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - van der Linden (Utrecht) (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - van der Veer (VU Amsterdam) (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - van Hout--Walters (Nijmegen) (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - van Parreren (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - van Rooijen (VU Amsterdam) (Box 7, Folder 27)
      - Vedder (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - Veling (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - Wagenaar – Institute for Perception TNO (Box 7, Folder 30)
      - Warries (Twente) (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Willemsen (Leiden) (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Dutch Navy – Women (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Norway
      - Bo (Oslo) (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Eckblad (Oslo) (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Eikeland (Bergen) (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Gjessing (Bergen) (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Helstrup (Bergen) (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Dan Olweus (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Dan Olweus, cont. (Bergen) (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Raahem (Bergen) (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Rabinowitz and Eikeland (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Rand, Gjesme, Nygard (Oslo) (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Gjesme (Oslo) (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Rund (Oslo) (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Skjelford (Oslo) (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Sovik (Trondheim) (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Smedslund (Oslo) (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Stinessen (Trondheim) (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Teigen (Bergen) (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Ulvund (Oslo) (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Undheim (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - Spacial Ability Papers (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Wold (Oslo) (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - South Africa
      - Miscellaneous South Africa papers, charts, and letters (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - Verster (Braamfontein) (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Spain
      - Madrid Conference and Paper (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - Seville Conference and Paper (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - de Oliveira (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - Rosa (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Silva (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous Spanish papers and pamphlets, including "I Congreso de Evaluacion Psicologica" Conference (Madrid) records (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Sweden
      - Old Scandanavian Papers (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Balke--Aurell (Goteborg) – (Empty folder) (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Bierschenk, B. (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Bjerstedt, A. and Sundgren, P. (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Bjerstedt, A. (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Educational and Psychological Interactions – from Malmo School of Education (Book, not in a folder) (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Brehmer, B. (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Brusling (Goteborg) (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Dornic (Stockholm) (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Ekman, Frobert, and Frankenhaeuser (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Ekehammer (Stockholm) (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Harnqvist, K. (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Five volumes of Pedagogiska Institutionen Goteborgs Universitet books – authored or co--authored by K. Harnqvist – not in a folder (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Hjelmquist (Goteborg) (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - Hosman, J. (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - Lindstrom (Goteborg) (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - Magnusson (Stockholm) (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - Magnusson – Pamphlets on education in Sweden (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - Svensson, A. (Goteborg) (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - Svensson, L. (Goteborg) (Box 9, Folder 2324)
      - Saljo (Goteborg) (Box 9, Folder 25)
      - Mashhour, M. (Box 9, Folder 26)
      - Montgomery and Biel, Goteborg (Box 9, Folder 27)
      - Shalit and Carlstedt (Box 9, Folder 28)
      - Svenson, O. (Stockholm) (Box 9, Folder 29)
      - Reports From the Department of Psychology – University of Stockholm – (unfoldered items) (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - University of Stockholm Psychology Reports (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Switzerland
      - Aebli, Reusser, Baer, and Marbach (Bern) (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Allal (Geneva) (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Bullinger (Geneva) (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Cardinet (Neuchatel) (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - de Ribaupierre (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Gasser (Lausanne) (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Grane (Bern) (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Papers and Pamphlets on Cognition and Eye Movements (in clear, plastic folder) (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Groner and Groner (Bern) (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Huberman (Geneva) (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Lang (Bern) (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Marbach (Bern) (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Oser (Fribourg) (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Jean--Luc Patry (Fribourg) (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - SSRE (Swiss Society for Research in Education) (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Stoll (Zurich) (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - United Kingdom
      - Brit Psych Society—Educ Section (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Experimental Psychology Society (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Cog and Learning Smr (Lancaster) (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Modeling Cognition (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Audley (NUFFIC) (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - Annett (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - MRC Applied Psychology Unit (Cambridge) (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - I D Brown MRC--APU (Cambridge) (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - Beaumont (Leicester) (Box 11, Folder 17)
      - Intelligence Research (Box 11, Folder 18)
      - Brand (Edinburgh) (Box 11, Folder 19)
      - Barker--Lunn (Box 11, Folder 20)
      - Black and Dockrell (Box 11, Folder 21)
      - Broadbent, D. E., E (Box 11, Folder 22)
      - Broadbent & Gregory, E (Box 11, Folder 23)
      - Brunel Work on Decisions, L (Box 11, Folder 24)
      - Knight--Godwin.Brit Navy Psychology, Admiralty Bldg. (Box 11, Folder 25)
      - Eysenck--Revolution in the Theory and Measurement of Intelligence (Box 11, Folder 26)
      - Folcard (Sussex) (Box 11, Folder 27)
      - Admiralty Marine Technology Establishment (Box 11, Folder 28)
      - Francis--Taylor (U London) (Misc ? Brit Educ Psych) (Box 11, Folder 29)
      - Hazel Frances (London) (Box 11, Folder 30)
      - Gilbert (Surrey) (Box 11, Folder 31)
      - Hamilton (Reading) (Box 11, Folder 32)
      - Irvine--Day (Plymouth) (Box 11, Folder 33)
      - Johnson--Laird, P.N., F (Box 11, Folder 34)
      - Levy (Lancaster) (Box 11, Folder 35)
      - Peel, E. A. (Leith) (Box 11, Folder 36)
      - Rabbitt (Manchester) (Box 11, Folder 37)
      - Reason (Box 11, Folder 38)
      - Reason (Manchester) (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Sloboda (Keele), Cog Proc in Mathematics (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Todd (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Young (Edinburgh) (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - BUPA Medical Center--British Computer Society--Prolog (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Nat Center for Systems Reliability (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - RHHI (London) Wilson, Symposium on Automated Psychological Testing, May 1984 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Arendt (Surry) (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Venezuela
      - Bolivar and Elawar (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Professional Papers, 1965-1997; Subseries 2
    - Book--Human Abilities (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Snow: Quotes, wise sayings, etc. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Snow--Annual Report, Cumulative (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Snow--Annual Report Materials, Sept. 1, 1977—Aug. 31, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Faculty Rebate Account (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Sabbatical and Leave of Absence (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Israel Medical Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Secty Position (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Faculty Review Committee (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Parking Problem (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Sears Position Argument (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Ambron Review [of paper by Sueann R. Ambron] (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Snow, R. E.—Professional File, Vita, etc. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Graduate Industrial Psychology (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Pretest "C" Pupils Correctness and Cons'ty Indices (Comp. 1 Tab 2) (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Stanford Correspondence, Jan 1, 1968 -Dec 31, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Stanford Correspondence, Jan 1, 1967 -Dec 31, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Stanford Correspondence, Jan 1, 1966 -Dec 31, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Stanford Correspondence, Jan 1, 1972 - (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Stanford Correspondence, Jan 1, 1971-Dec 31, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Stanford Correspondence, Jan 1, 1970 -Dec 31, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Stanford Correspondence, Jan 1, 1969-Dec 31, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Old Correspondence (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Unlabeled folder [Rijksuniversiteit, Leiden, 1973] (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 13, Folder 1013)
    - Correspondence Jan 1974 - (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence Jan 1973- (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence Jan 1975- (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence Jan 1976- (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence Jan -Dec 77 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence Jan 1978- (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence 1979 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Unfoldered material [1978-1979 correspondence] (Box 14)
    - SUSE Correspondence 1980-81 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence at CASBS 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Snow--CASBS (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Unfoldered material (Box 14)
    - Bhatia (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Unfoldered material (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence Non ONRI (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - 16mm tape: Film Memoryy III (Box 15)
    - 7" audio reel "Memory for Ideas," 1967 (Box 15)
    - 7" audio reel "Sentence Reproduction," 1967 (Box 15)
    - Cinepsychometry (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Seibert and Snow (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - [Unlabeled folder] (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Cine--Psychometry I (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Unfoldered material (Box 15)
    - Motion Picture Testing--References (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Booklet: Studies in Cine--Psychometry II (Box 15)
    - [Unlabeled folder] (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Unfoldered material (Box 15)
    - Systems Analysis Consultation January 1970 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Functional Uniqueness (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Unfoldered material (Box 15)
    - Acting Directorship Notes and Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Center Business (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - My Agreement with Center on Program Director Slot (Box 15, Folder 11)